Tufts Dental Yearbook and Senior Biographies UP143
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Tufts Dental Yearbook and Senior Biographies
1914 -- 2018
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
School of Dental Medicine
UP143
0.75 Linear Feet
49 Volumes
1 Audiovisual Object(s)
Arrangement
This collection is organized into one series.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains annual yearbooks for the School of Dental Medicine between 1914 and 2009. For most years it has been known as the Explorer, though the first edition in 1914 was called Dentufts. In 2000 the format was changed and they were no longer referred to as yearbooks, but Senior Biography Books. The 1921 yearbook is located in collection MS149.
Related Materials
MS149, Soorien Simon Alexander papers and dental instruments, DCA
Biographical / Historical
Tufts University School of Dental Medicine was established in 1868 as Boston Dental College. It was incorporated into Tufts College in 1899. Although founded as a school to educate students from New England, today Tufts is renowned throughout the United States and the world as a center for academic and clinical excellence. Tufts boasts over 6,900 alumni composed of individuals from all fifty states and thirty-nine countries. The majority of the alumni outside of the USA have completed an Advanced Education Certificate program. Students receive a comprehensive education emphasizing the importance of didactic coursework, clinical experience, and practice management that prepares them to enter the work force as confident, proficient clinicians.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
- Tufts Dental Yearbook and Senior Biographies, 1914 -- 2018; UP143.001; 0.75 Linear Feet; 49 Volumes; 1 Audiovisual Object(s)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains the yearbook for the School of Dental Medicine. For most years it has been known as the Explorer, though the first edition in 1914 was called Dentufts. In 2000 the name was changed to Senior Biography Book.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged loosely by chronology.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Dentufts, 1914; UP143.001.029.00001 (Box 29)
    Leather-bound volume with bios and pictures.
  - Dentufts, 1918; UP143.000072 (Volume 1918)
    Content Warning
    This yearbook contains racist and antisemitic content. For more information on DCA's content warning policy please visit our website.
  - Dentufts, 1921; UP143.001.053.00001 (Volume 1921)
  - Explorer, 1915; UP143.001.054.00001 (Volume 1915)
  - Explorer, 1924; UP143.001.055.00001 (Volume 1924)
  - Explorer, 1930; UP143.001.051.00001 (Box Volume 51)
    Belonged to Hurant Sherman Santoian, donated by his daughter, Barbara Tomasian.
  - Explorer, 1932; UP143.001.056.00001 (Volume 1932)
  - Explorer, 1935; UP143.001.001.00001 (Box Volume 1)
  - Explorer, 1937; UP143.001.002.00001 (Box Volume 2)
  - Explorer, 1938; UP143.001.052.00001; 1 Volumes (Volume 52)
  - Explorer, 1939; UP143.001.003.00001 (Box Volume 3)
    This yearbook was donated by Sandy Doorey on behalf of Dr. Philip Coviello, D 1939. Deceased 10/22/2004.
  - Explorer, 1940; UP143.001.004.00001 (Box Volume 4)
  - Explorer, 1941; UP143.001.005.00001 (Box Volume 5)
  - Explorer, 1942; UP143.001.006.00001 (Box Volume 6)
  - Explorer, 1943; UP143.001.007.00001 (Box Volume 7)
  - Explorer, 1943-12-01; UP143.001.008.00001 (Box Volume 8)
  - Explorer, 1944; UP143.001.009.00001 (Box Volume 9)
  - Explorer, 1946; UP143.001.010.00001 (Box Volume 10)
  - Explorer, 1947; UP143.001.011.00001 (Box Volume 11)
  - Explorer, 1948; UP143.001.012.00001 (Box Volume 12)
  - Explorer, 1949 -- 1951; UP143.001.013.00001 (Box Volume 13)
  - Explorer, 1950; UP143.001.057.00001 (Volume 1950)
  - Explorer, 1951; UP143.001.046.00001 (Box Volume 46)
  - Explorer, 1952; UP143.001.014.00001 (Box Volume 14)
  - Explorer, 1953; UP143.001.015.00001 (Box Volume 15)
  - Explorer, 1954; UP143.001.016.00001 (Box Volume 16)
  - Explorer, 1956; UP143.001.017.00001 (Box Volume 17)
  - Explorer, 1957; UP143.001.018.00001 (Box Volume 18)
  - Explorer, 1958; UP143.001.019.00001 (Box Volume 19)
  - Explorer, 1959; UP143.001.020.00001 (Box Volume 20)
  - Explorer, 1960; UP143.001.021.00001 (Box Volume 21)
  - Explorer, 1961; UP143.001.022.00001 (Box Volume 22)
  - Explorer, 1962; UP143.001.023.00001 (Box Volume 23)
  - Explorer, 1963; UP143.001.024.00001 (Box Volume 24)
  - Explorer, 1964; UP143.001.025.00001 (Box Volume 25)
  - Explorer, 1965; UP143.001.026.00001 (Box Volume 26)
  - Explorer, 1966; UP143.001.027.00001 (Box Volume 27)
  - Explorer, 1968; UP143.001.028.00001 (Box Volume 28)
  - Explorer, 1969; UP143.001.030.00001 (Box Volume 30)
  - Explorer, 1970; UP143.001.031.00001 (Box Volume 31)
  - Explorer, 1971; UP143.001.032.00001 (Box Volume 32)
  - Explorer, 1972; UP143.001.047.00001 (Box Volume 47)
  - Explorer, 1973; UP143.001.033.00001 (Box Volume 33)
  - Tufts Atlas of Dentistry, 1977; UP143.001.048.00001 (Box Volume 48)
  - Explorer, 1978; UP143.001.049.00001 (Box Volume 49)
  - Explorer, 1980; UP143.001.034.00001 (Box Volume 34)
  - Explorer, 1981; UP143.001.035.00001 (Box Volume 35)
  - Explorer, 1982; UP143.001.036.00001 (Box Volume 36)
  - Explorer, 1983; UP143.001.037.00001 (Box Volume 37)
  - Explorer, 1988; UP143.001.038.00001 (Box Volume 38)
  - Explorer, 1989; UP143.001.039.00001 (Box Volume 39)
  - Explorer, 1990; UP143.001.040.00001 (Box Volume 40)
  - Explorer, 1992; UP143.001.041.00001 (Box Volume 41)
  - Explorer, 1994; UP143.001.045.00001 (Box Volume 45)
  - Explorer, 1995; UP143.001.029.00002 (Box 29)
    16 page booklet with pictures rather than a bigger yearbook.
  - Explorer, 1996; UP143.001.042.00001 (Box Volume 42)
  - Yearbook, 1997; UP143.001.043.00001 (Box 43)
    produced by Anthony S. Prezioso
    videocassette
  - Explorer, 1998; UP143.001.044.00001 (Box Volume 44)
  - Senior Biographies, 2000; UP143.001.029.00003 (Box 29)
    Soft cover booklet "Class of 2000 Senior Dinner & Biographies."
  - Senior Biographies, 2001; UP143.001.029.00004 (Box 29)
    Soft cover booklet "Class of 2001" May 20, 2001.
    Dental Medicine Alumni Association
  - Senior Biographies, 2002; UP143.001.029.00005 (Box 29)
    Soft cover booklet "Class of 2002" May 19, 2002.
  - Senior Biographies, 2003; UP143.001.029.00006 (Box 29)
    Soft cover booklet "Class of 2003" May 18, 2003.
  - Senior Biographies, 2004; UP143.001.029.00007 (Box 29)
    Soft cover booklet "Class of 2004" May 23, 2004.
  - Senior Biographies, 2005-05-23; UP143.001.029.00008 (Box 29)
    Soft cover booklet "Class of 2005" May 23, 2005.
  - Senior Biographies, Class of 2006, 2006-05-21; UP143.001.050.00001 (Box 50)
  - Senior Biographies, Class of 2007, 2007-05-20; UP143.001.050.00002 (Box 50)
  - Senior Biographies, Class of 2008, 2008-05-18; UP143.001.050.00003 (Box 50)
  - Senior Biographies, Class of 2009, 2009-05-17; UP143.001.050.00004 (Box 50)
  - Senior Biographies, Class of 2011, 2011-05-22; UP143.001.050.00005 (Box 50)
  - Senior Biographies, Class of 2014, 2014-05-18; UP143.001.050.00006 (Box 50)
  - Senior Biographies, Class of 2015, 2015-05-17; UP143.001.050.00007 (Box 50)
  - Senior Biographies, Class of 2018, 2018-05-20; UP143.001.050.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 50, Box 8)
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Accession UP-2018-063